Rule the Court
Come on, Seijou!
ゴゴレツゴレツゴ伊達工
オオオ青城青城
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
Let's go, Date Tech!
The Iron Wall of Date
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
お願いします
Let's have a good match!
しァス
Yeah.
Now, now. Don't be so tense.
まあまあそんなに気張んないで
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
You guys still have next year.
君らは来年だてあるんだし
関係ねぇスよ
That's irrelevant.
立場とかそういうのコトに入たら関係ない
Your reputation or status doesn't matter once you're on the court.
I know, right?
だよね知てる
Heads is Seijou, tails is Date Tech.
表が青城裏が伊達工です
３年だろうが１年だろうが強い方が強く
It doesn't matter if you're a first-year or a third-year.
The better team wins,
ただボルを落とした方が負ける
and the team who lets the ball hit the floor loses.
よしゃ
All right!
It's that simple.
シンプルな話だ
Episode Eighteen:
The Losers
It's going out of bounds!
アウト
Shake it off! Focus on the next one!
ドンマイ次次
My bad!
すみません
大した本数打てないのに
I haven't even hit that many spikes,
yet I've managed to mess up three this set.
このセト俺のスパイクミス三本目
Waku South                   Karasuno
アチャどうしたんだろう
Man, what's wrong with him?
慣れてないライトに入てるのもあると思うけど
I think it's partially due to him not used to being on the right side.
One point at a time!
But the biggest factor is probably the pressure he's under.
でもやぱ一番はプレシャなのかもな
一本
しゃワンチ
Got it.
I touched it!
オライ
Damn, they're actually pretty good.
くそやぱうめぇ
Waku South                      Karasuno
All right!
よしゃ
和久南は中島が調子上げてきてるな
Waku South's Nakashima seems to really be in the groove now.
On the other hand, it seems like Karasuno is struggling with that.
逆に烏野はイマイチ乗れねぇよな
Hey!
You got a look on your face like the world's going to end.
お前だけ地球滅亡みたいな顔してるぞ
滅亡早ぇぞ
It's too early for the world to end.
地球防衛軍
I'm the Earth Defense Force!
そんな顔してないつの
I do not look like that!
All right! Chikara's back in action!
よしゃ力復活
Not much you can do if you get completely blown away, but there are still some balls that you can dig out!
フ飛ばされたら仕方ねぇが
Calm down.
落ち着け引きずるな
I can't keep dwelling on it.
拾えるものもあんぞ
これ以上足を引張るわけにはいかない
I've gotta do this! Like Daichi would!
You're landing a lot of your attacks. Keep it going!
やるんだ大地さんみたいに
攻撃はよく決まてる繋いでけ
Yes, sir!
Coach!
Huh?
So the Little Giant was like Waku South's number one?
小さな巨人はあの和久南の１番の人みたいな感じだたんですか
Well, the way he plays is probably the closest in the prefecture.
そうだな今の県内ではプレイスタイルが一番近いかもな
Hey, don't try to compete with him.
おい張り合おうとすんなよ
He's better in mid-air battles than you are.
空中戦のテクニクは向こうが数段上だ
Just play like you usually do.
いつも通りやれ
Why are you always such a buzzkill?!
どうしてお前はそうやて人の心を折るんですか
That was just some kind advice!
親切なアドバイスだろうが
You call that kind?!
親切とは
I know that he's good!
H-Hinata, calm down...
向こうがうまいなんてわかてんじゃん
日向落ち着いて
That's why I'm trying to figure out what to do!
だからどうしようかてハナシだろ
You don't have a brain, so don't even bother trying.
ない頭使てどうすんだ
What was that?!
なんだと
Waku South                         Karasuno
猛
Takeru!
That was a really risky straight spike!
すげぇ際どいストレト
He's so good!
うめぇ
ナイスキ
Nice spike!
You aren't even 170 cm tall.
１７０センチにも満たない身長
お前も確かにすごいけど
Give us another good serve, Tabi!
I can't deny your skills, but I'm not going to lose to you.
タビ一本ナイサ
おう任せろ
Yeah, leave it to me!
俺はここでは負けないよ
I'm going to surpass the Little Giant, not you!
小さな巨人を超えるのはこの俺だ
Waku South
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
危ねぇ
Crap!
Hinata, it's all yours!
日向ラスト
Yeah!
I'm going to go for a wipe.
ブロクアウト狙う
He really hit that one out of the park.
特大ホムラン
I'm sorry!
すみません
As Kageyama said, Nakashima is clearly better right now on an individual level.
影山の言う通り現段階での個人技は完全に中島に軍配だな
ドンマイドンマイ
It's fine!
I told you not to try to compete with him, moron!
張り合うなつたろボケェ
Do it one more time, Tabi!
タビもう一本ナイサ
Got it!
オライ
I hit it right at him.
正面か
All right, we dug it out!
よし拾た
Two blockers!
ブロク２枚
Damn, not again!
So fast!
速
危ない
Look out!
Counterattack!
カウンタだ
Your skills are no match for Nakashima's or the Little Giant's right now.
お前はまだ中島やかつての小さな巨人に技術で及ばない
But...
you can still fight with everything you've learned!
身につけた全部でなら戦える
Yeah!
Are you all right?!
大丈夫か
勢いつけ過ぎた
I got overexcited.
Be careful! Seriously, be careful!
気をつけてホント気をつけて
Bumping into a guy this light is nothing.
こんな軽い奴とぶつかても何ともないス
That spike was awesome!
すげぇよナイスキ
Even if we're backed into a corner, we still have
the firepower to push through. That's our weapon.
追い詰められても
そこをぶち抜く火力があるのがうちの武器です
Kageyama actually said something decent!
影山がまともなこと言てる
I think you said something like that once.
て感じのこと前に縁下さんに言われたなと
Oh, that's right.
そう言えば
Yeah.
そうだな
S-Sorry, sir. Are you all right?
すすまん先生大丈夫か
I got knocked flat on my back.
ひくり返ちゃいました
毎日顔面を擦ていたとは思えない
It's hard to believe he used to struggle with diving receives after that one.
フライングレシブでしたね
Yeah.
Let's see your killer serve!
行け殺人サブ
Their number ten has amazing reflexes and mobility.
烏野の１０番なんつ反射と機動力
Waku South
Shiro!
A tip!
フェイント
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Let it go!
アウトアウト
Sorry for the low set!
トス低かたスンマセン
I could see the tip coming, but I started moving too late.
フェイントのモションは見えてたのに出遅れた
Daichi would've been able to get that ball to the setter properly.
大地さんなら多分セタにちゃんと返したはずだ
I'm sorry.
すんません
What's that supposed to mean?
すみませんて何よ
You're about ten years away from being able to do what Daichi...
大地さんと全く同じ働きしようなんてな１０年
No, that's too long.
は長いな
You're about a year away from that!
１年くらい早ぇ
That just now was a good receive, no matter what anyone says!
今のは誰が何と言おうと「ナイスレシブ」だ
Let's not mention any realistic numbers like "one year."
１年とかリアルな数字やめろよ
Karasuno
Someone get it!
Takeru!
猛
All right!
よしゃ
Damn it!
It's gonna be rough if they can't do something about that wipe.
あのブロクアウトもう少しなんとかしないと苦しいな
You nearly got it! Don't worry!
おしいぞドンマイ
I don't have the time to wallow in my failures right now.
一々メンタルにダメジ食らてる余裕ない
Playing on par with Daichi just isn't possible for me as things stand.
大地さんに劣る技術は今すぐどうこうできることじゃない
I know that he's good!
向こうがうまいなんてわかてんじゃん
That's why I'm trying to figure out what to do!
だからどうしようかてハナシだろ
Hey, can I have a moment?
あのちょといいですか
When their number one goes for a wipe,
I'll chase after the ball.
あの１番がブロクアウト狙てきたボル俺が拾います
Tanaka and Asahi, you two are way better at digging out powerful spikes than I am.
田中と旭さんの方が俺より強打のレシブうまいから
So I want you two to defend against straight spikes,
二人にはストレト側守てもらて
and I'll stay back in the middle to try to get any balls that go that way.
俺は真ん中の深いところでフ飛ばされたボル拾います
I can't guarantee that it'll work, but...
うまくいくとは言い切れないですが
Yeah, let's give it a shot.
おうそれやてみんべ
Th-Thank you very much!
あありがとうございます
Can I dig out powerful spikes better than Ennoshita?
俺縁下より強打取れか
オライ
Got it!
All right!
猛さん
Takeru!
Yeah!
Two blockers!
ブロク２枚
うまくいくとは言い切れないですが
I can't guarantee that it'll work, but...
おうそれやてみんべ
Yeah, let's give it a shot.
これを拾えなければ
If I can't save this...
I don't deserve to stand on this court!
このコトで俺に価値はない
Ennoshita!
縁下
Damn...
Make it!
繋げ
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
Ennoshita!
縁下
Damn...
Hinata, it's all yours!
日向ラスト
Three blockers!
ブロク３枚
If I just spike it, they'll block it.
打てば捕まる
Let's regroup.
立て直す
こいつ
He...
All right!
しゃオライ
Got it!
What? Did he hit the block on purpose?
今ブロクに当てたのてわざと
That was a rebound.
リバウンドですね
When did he learn that?
そんなのどこで
夏の合宿の時に
During the summer training camp.
But that was pure luck.
でも絶対マグレですよ
Let me have another shot!
もう一回
With Daichi absent, our defense is weaker than usual.
大地の不在いつもより不安定な守備
意図的か無意識か
Whether intentionally or not,
来いやぁ
Bring it!
Hinata's trying to deal with this situation.
日向もこの事態に対処しようとしている
今のすげぇぞ日向
That was awesome, Hinata!
I feel like someone's complimenting me!
誰かが俺を褒めてる気がする
That'd never happen.
気のせいですね
Where'd you learn that?!
どこで覚えてきた
実は合宿の時に木兎さんに
Actually, Bokuto taught me it during the training camp.
烏野にはすごいチビがいるのはわかてはいた
I knew that Karasuno had an amazing short guy,
ナニずるいぞお前
What? No fair!
You lucky bastard!
羨ましいやつめ
but I thought that was only because of the setter.
でもそれはセタありきでのことだと思ていた
You should've told me earlier!
それ言とけよ
And yet...
Good job, Hinata, Tanaka!
よし日向田中ナイスキ
Chikara!
力
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive.
That's no fair, Noya.
ずるいノヤさんはずるい
Getting a compliment from him about a receive would cheer anyone up.
西谷にレシブ褒められたらそら奮い立つわな
He's in.
入たな
Pardon?
He's just a substitute, and he can't completely blend in with the vibe on the court since he doesn't belong.
自分はあくまで代替品であり
出来上がているコト内の空気に完全に溶け込むことはできない
I think that's how Ennoshita used to feel.
そういう気持ちが縁下にあたように思う
But I think the last play took care of that.
でも今のプレでなくなたんじゃねぇか
How so?
今のプレが
自分で考え仲間に伝えて実行する
He came up with the plan,
told the rest of the team, and then executed it.
そういうプレは自信になるもんだ
That sort of thing builds confidence.
I see.
なるほど
It's difficult.
難しい
よしゃあ
All right!
烏野つい最近まで特別強くも弱くもない
Until recently, Karasuno was an
average team that didn't stand out.
目立たないチムだた
He's the Little Giant!
まさに「小さな巨人」
身長のことを気にし始めた頃
Back when I first started to worry about my height,
that match showed me there was a path I could take.
これはいいコス
He aimed that spike perfectly!
He has amazing vision!
こういう道があるのだと教えてくれた試合
Karasuno's number ten.
烏野の１０番
He wears the same uniform as the Little Giant did.
あの時の「小さな巨人」と同じ背番号を背負うやつ
もう一本
One more!
Takeru!
猛
Number one is doing a back row attack!
まずはお前を倒していく
I'll start by defeating you!
１番バクアタク
Karasuno
Waku South
しゃあ
Karasuno
Waku South
All right!
Karasuno
Waku South
We caught up!
追いついた
Karasuno
Waku South
Sorry, the set was low.
すまんトス低かたな
Give us a good serve, Ennoshita!
縁下ナイサ
Got it!
オライ
ナイス
おしゃあ
Nice!
All right!
よかた
Thank goodness.
Even though you're older than Takeru, sometimes it feels like the reverse.
勇兄と猛兄長男と次男本当は逆なんじゃないの
You're gonna make me cry!
兄ちゃん泣くぞ
Karasuno                       Waku South
旭さんナイサ
Give us a good one, Asahi!
Sorry! I hit it too far!
すんません長い
ネト越えるぞ
It's going over the net!
Takeru!
Kageyama, push it over!
猛さん
影山押し込め
こういう時に嫌というほど思い知る
It's at times like this that I'm painfully reminded
高さの壁
of the wall called height.
Nice save, Tabi!
ナイスカバタビ
Keep it going!
繋げ
烏野１０番俺はお前に負けない
Karasuno's number ten, I won't lose to you!
Takeru!
猛
I won't lose,
俺自身も仲間の頼もしさも
and neither will my teammates' bravery!
よしゃあ
All right!
Karasuno                   Waku South
Hang in there.
耐えろよ粘ていれば必ず向こうもミスが出る
If you keep it up, they'll start making mistakes.
On top of that, they're missing their captain.
まして向こうは主将が不在
Hang in there until they crack.
相手が崩れる瞬間まで耐えろ
Yes, sir!
それと
Lastly,
go show them who's really the Little Giant in this match.
今この場の「小さな巨人」が誰なのか知らしめて来い
Yes, sir!
Waku South
Hinata, your serve!
日向サブ
Right!
Mr. Ukai...
烏養さんが
Huh?
終盤だし東峰さんにトス集めてもいいかもなてさ
He was saying that it might be better to start giving sets to Azumane since the match is almost over.
Right.
Watch for a fast attack!
速攻来るぞ
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
日向が下がて向こうも絶対東峰さんを一番意識する
Now that Hinata's in the back row,
they're definitely going to be cautious of Azumane.
The best time to set the ball to him...
東峰さんに上げるのはそれがベストの時
should be...
今は
こちだ
right now!
All right!
しゃあ
It's in bounds! Thank goodness.
入たよかた
力
Chikara!
Even though the match is on the line,
he set it to someone who hasn't gotten many spikes off.
終盤の貴重なチャンスにあえて打数の少ない６番に回す
Nice spike, Ennoshita!
縁下ナイスキ
That first-year setter is definitely gutsy.
肝据わてやがんなこの１年セタ
Damn, I'm not sure if I should be happy about this or not.
チクショウ悔しいような嬉しいような
Karasuno
旭さんナイサ
Give us a good one, Asahi!
Give 'em a fierce one!
強烈なの行け
Finish the match off in one go!
ここで一気に突き放せ
It's out!
アウト
All right!
よしゃあ
Nice eye!
ナイスジャジ
I'm sor—
すみま
Let's get the next one!
次一本す
Karasuno                   Waku South
Don't look at the score...
Give us a good serve, Matsushima!
松島ナイサ
点差を見るな
Calm down. Stay calm.
落ち着け平常心
Oh crap!
ヤバイ
Let it go!
アウト
Nice call!
ナイスジャジ
すすみません
I-I'm sor—
はい切り替え
Okay, let's change gears!
次取れば問題なし
There's no problem if we get the next one!
おい松島次前衛に回てきた時
Hey, Matsushima!
If you're still depressed when you rotate back to the front row, I'm gonna make you buy me a popsicle!
まだ凹んでたらアイスを奢らす
Right!
Karasuno                     Waku South
Karasuno's at match point.
烏野マチポイントだ
And here comes Karasuno's number ten again.
あららここで烏野の１０番来ちゃた
Waku South's in trouble.
和久南ピンチじゃん
Got it!
オライ
All right!
夕が抜けてたとこ狙てな
They targeted the spot Yuu left open?
They're calm.
冷静だな
You can do this, Kawatabi!
川渡さんナイサ
タビここ一本
Tabi, get this one!
これミスたら即終わりかよ
If I mess this up, it's all over.
You'll look really cool if you hit this one as hard as you can.
ここ全力で打たらかこいいぞ
It's up! Nice job, Nishinoya!
上がた西谷ナイス
It's in a bad location!
乱れたでも速攻行けなくもない
影山
Kageyama!
But a fast attack is still possible!
Got it!
オライ
Or should I let Tanaka have it?
それとも田中さんに任す
No, a fast attack can make it!
いやでも
早いの行ける
It's a bit high?
少し高い
焦たか
They rushed it!
耐えろ相手が崩れる瞬間まで
Hang in there until they crack.
チャンスボル
Here's our chance!
Hinata!
日向
バタバタしないいいジャンプは
Don't flail about!
A good jump...
...starts with a good approach!
いい助走から
At this point, we no longer have the advantage of Karasuno's captain being absent.
もはや烏野の主将がいないアドバンテジは
うちにはないか
ボル見ろよ
Eye on the ball!
Yeah.
もう遅い
It's too late!
All...
しゃああ
...right!
Karasuno                   Waku South
Thank you for the match!
ありがとうございました
何だよ
What?
あの１番との真向勝負勝てなかた
I couldn't beat their number one head-to-head.
He was more like the Little Giant than I was.
俺より「小さな巨人」だた
Of course. You're not even good enough to shine the Little Giant's shoes, you moron.
当たり前だろうが１００年早ぇこのボケが
Hey! What are you guys doing?!
ほら何やてんだお前ら
Come on, line up!
ほれほれ整列整列
Bow.
挨拶
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました
したあ
よく頑張たわ猛
You fought hard, Takeru!
Today was just our second match.
今日は二試合次の相手はもと強敵
Our next opponent will be even harder.
Daichi!
大地さん
Uh, um...
ああえと
I'm sorry.
すまん
D-D-D...
大地さん
Daichi!
大地
D-Daichi! A-Are...
大地さん大
I'm fine.
大丈夫だよ
No, seriously. I got some rest.
I actually feel better than before the match.
いやまじでかなりちゃんと休んだし
むしろ試合前より元気
I'll work twice as hard in the next match.
次の試合は人一倍働くから
お前らのほうがフルセトやて消耗してんだろ
You guys must be exhausted from playing all three sets.
Come on, rest.
ほら休め休め
Oh, our next opponent's playing right now.
今ちょうど対戦相手やてるんだけ
I was watching from around the 20-point mark.
２０点目くらいから見てたよ
At first, I thought I needed to get back out there soon as possible.
最初は一刻も早く戻ろうと思てたんだけど
実際にお前ら見たら
But when I actually saw you guys in action, I knew everything would be okay.
ああ大丈夫だて思た
I even felt like I'd ruin the rhythm you guys had if I went back out.
むしろ今俺が出ていたらリズム崩すと思たよ
Good job with that last receive, Ennoshita.
ラストのあれナイスレシブ縁下
Right.
Sorry.
ごめん
Could you go on ahead?
ちょと先行てて
Doesn't Ennoshita seem a bit down considering we won?
縁下テンション低くない勝たのに
Yeah.
I messed up half the spikes I hit,
スパイクは打た半分がミスだたし
and I only made some real receives in the second half of the match.
レシブでまともに働いたのは後半だけ
But for the first time, I felt like I left it all on the court.
でも初めてちゃんと最後まで戦えた気がする
So why...
なのに
Why am I so relieved?!
安心してんじゃねぇよ
次どこが勝ち上がてこようが
I should be getting ready to take on whoever we end up playing next!
戦てやるて思えよバカ
I'm such a damn idiot!
このクソクソクソ
That was amazing!
すごいね最後澤村さんと見てたよ
I was watching the last bit with Sawamura!
We're gonna win the next match too!
次も勝つ
Doesn't Yamaguchi seem down?
山口くん元気なくない
Sorry.
ごめんちょと便所行てくる
I'm gonna go to the bathroom,
so go on ahead without me.
から先行てて
He's really pumped about going to the bathroom.
ずいぶん気合入れて便所行くんだな
He must need to shit.
クソなんだろ
Say "poop"! You're so vulgar, Kageyama!
うんこて言えよ影山くんお下品
トイレに行たんじゃないと思うけど
I don't think he's actually going to the bathroom.
Hey, Takeru. It's time for the meeting.
おい猛ミティングだぞ
なんか
You know...
Huh?
The end happened in slow motion.
最後スロモションだた
あの一瞬に１０番と目が合て
I locked eyes with number ten.
I could tell that he figured out where I was aiming for.
俺がブロクアウトでどこを狙てるのか
あいつが分かたのが分かた
ここまで見えたのて初めてだ
That was the first time I was able to see it so clearly.
It gave me goosebumps.
ぞくと来たよ
Let me...
もう一回
もう一回やらせてくれよ
Let me have another chance!
Aoba Jousai
Attack! Attack, attack, attack, attack, Seijou!
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
行け行け行け行け行け青城
ゴゴレツゴレツゴ伊達工
Rule the Court
Work it, work it, work it, Seijou!
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
The Iron Wall of Date
Hey, don't eat too much.
おい食いすぎんなよ
Now...
let's see who our next opponent will be.
次の相手どちだろうな
Lately, I've been conflicted as a coach because everyone's doing so well.
なんかここんとこ皆しかりしてきて
コチとしては複雑だぜ
And Nishinoya keeps scolding me.
俺も西谷にだめだしされぱなしなんで
Wanna join me?
お前もどうだ
Uh, I'm a minor!
いや俺未成年ですて
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Nineteen:
The Iron Wall Can Be Built Again and Again
次回ハイキュ鉄壁は何度でも築かれる
"The Iron Wall Can Be Built Again and Again."